<!--
Copyright (c) 2026 Nomikosi Consulting

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->

<idea-plugin>
    <!-- NOTE: the id is permanent once the plugin is published. -->
    <id>com.codex.desktreadmill</id>
    <name>Treadmill Buddy</name>
    <vendor email="hello@nomikosi.dev" url="https://github.com/nomikosi/Treadmill-Buddy">Nomikosi Consulting</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p><b>Treadmill Buddy</b> is a digital stopwatch for developers who walk while they code.</p>
        <p>Track under-desk treadmill sessions from inside IntelliJ IDEA with a large digital clock, floating movable clock, saved sessions, distance, steps, calories, and goal countdowns.</p>
        <ul>
            <li><b>Marathon:</b> open-ended count-up sessions.</li>
            <li><b>Calorie burn:</b> count down from the time needed to burn a calorie target.</li>
            <li><b>KG burn:</b> count down from the time needed to burn a target mass in kg.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>The plugin includes selectable calorie algorithms, a Settings page for profile/defaults, live speed recalculation, live calorie-algorithm recalculation, saved session deletion, and configurable auto-pause after keyboard inactivity.</p>
        <p>License: Apache License 2.0</p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <ul>
            <li>1.0.2:
                <ul>
                    <li>Fully remove the deprecated file-chooser constructor reference flagged by the Marketplace verifier (resolved at runtime for 2024.3 and 2025.1+ compatibility).</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>1.0.1:
                <ul>
                    <li>Replace a deprecated file-chooser API flagged by the Marketplace verifier.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>1.0.0:
                <ul>
                    <li>Metric / imperial unit setting (km/h-kg-cm or mph-lb-in), switchable any time; stored data stays metric and converts in the UI.</li>
                    <li>Optional daily goal (steps, distance, or calories) with a progress bar in the tool window and a once-per-day notification when reached.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>0.3.0:
                <ul>
                    <li>Incline support with the full ACSM grade equations.</li>
                    <li>Optional "time to move" reminder after a configurable sitting time.</li>
                    <li>14-day distance chart and walking-day streak in the tool window.</li>
                    <li>Actions for start/pause, save, and new session in the Tools menu, tool window title bar, and status bar popup - bindable to shortcuts.</li>
                    <li>Inline field validation instead of modal error dialogs.</li>
                    <li>Session deletion is now undoable from a notification.</li>
                    <li>Saved sessions sorted newest first; floating clock remembers position and pin state.</li>
                    <li>Age removed from the profile - no algorithm used it.</li>
                    <li>Dark plugin icon, message-bundle scaffolding, and Marketplace signing/publishing pipeline.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>0.2.0:
                <ul>
                    <li>Drift-proof session timing based on wall-clock deltas instead of raw timer ticks.</li>
                    <li>One shared workout engine across all project windows; sessions keep running when the tool window is closed.</li>
                    <li>Status bar widget with live time and calories; click to pause/resume.</li>
                    <li>Dark-theme support for the seven-segment clock.</li>
                    <li>Completion and save confirmations are now notifications instead of modal dialogs.</li>
                    <li>Saved sessions list with toolbar, session details, keyboard support, and CSV export.</li>
                    <li>Today / 7 days / all-time totals for distance and calories.</li>
                    <li>Auto-pause now counts mouse activity too, and pauses after system sleep instead of crediting slept time.</li>
                    <li>Floating clock gained a Pin (always on top) toggle.</li>
                    <li>Proper resource cleanup on tool window close and plugin unload.</li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>0.1.0: Initial Treadmill Buddy release with digital stopwatch, floating clock, saved sessions, calorie algorithms, countdown modes, and configurable profile settings.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <resource-bundle>messages.TreadmillBundle</resource-bundle>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <toolWindow
                id="Treadmill Buddy"
                anchor="right"
                icon="/icons/treadmill.svg"
                factoryClass="com.codex.desktreadmill.TreadmillToolWindowFactory"/>
        <applicationConfigurable
                instance="com.codex.desktreadmill.settings.TreadmillConfigurable"
                displayName="Treadmill Buddy"/>
        <postStartupActivity implementation="com.codex.desktreadmill.startup.TreadmillStartupActivity"/>
        <statusBarWidgetFactory
                id="TreadmillBuddyWidget"
                implementation="com.codex.desktreadmill.ui.TreadmillStatusBarWidgetFactory"/>
        <notificationGroup id="Treadmill Buddy" displayType="BALLOON"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <group id="TreadmillBuddy.Group" popup="true">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <action id="TreadmillBuddy.TogglePause"
                    class="com.codex.desktreadmill.actions.TogglePauseAction"
                    icon="AllIcons.Actions.Resume"/>
            <action id="TreadmillBuddy.SaveSession"
                    class="com.codex.desktreadmill.actions.SaveSessionAction"
                    icon="AllIcons.Actions.MenuSaveall"/>
            <action id="TreadmillBuddy.NewSession"
                    class="com.codex.desktreadmill.actions.NewSessionAction"
                    icon="AllIcons.General.Add"/>
            <action id="TreadmillBuddy.OpenToolWindow"
                    class="com.codex.desktreadmill.actions.OpenToolWindowAction"/>
        </group>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
